[Oh no! We forgot!]
[We should have done something
on The Toyako Summit!]
[Note: 38th G8 Summit took place in Lake Toya, Hokkaido,
which is also the name of Gintoki's wooden sword.]
[Oedo Mart]
(栗子)
とろりんｼｭｰｸﾘｰﾑｼﾞｬﾝﾎﾞ ｴﾋﾞｸﾞﾗﾀﾝ➡
One creamy jumbo cream
puff, one shrimp gratin...
大盛り豚ﾄﾛ弁当 以上３点
1,038円になりまする｡
One jumbo pork jowl meat lunch.
All together, that's 1,038 yen.
ﾒﾀﾎﾞに気をつけてくださりませ｡
Please watch your weight.
ありがとうございましたで
ございまする｡
Thank you very much.
Kuriko-chan, aren't you tired?
栗子ちゃん 疲れたでしょう？
Want to take a break with me?
一緒に 休憩とりましょうか？
はいでございまする｡
Sure.
ちょっと！
なんで お前と一緒なんだよ!?
Hey, why is she taking
a break with you?!
そうだよ！ 抜け駆けすんなよ!!
That's right! No cheating!
Shut up!
うるせえな！
だったら ｵﾚと休憩するって～の！
Why don't you take a break with me?!
What are you saying? With me!!
何 言ってるんだよ！ ｵﾚとだ!!
ﾎﾞｸとだよね～ 栗子ちゃん！
Say, you want to take a break with
me, don't you, Kuriko-chan?
違うよ ｵﾚとだよね？
ｵﾚとだよね？
No, with me, right?
With me, right?
Want to fight?!
(さわぎ声)
Bring it on, damn it!!
Step outside!!
["They Say Soy Sauce On Pudding Tastes Like Sea Urchin, But Soy Sauce On Pudding Only Tastes Like Pudding and Soy Sauce"]
(松平)かわいい子には 旅をさせろ
そうは言うがな｡
As the saying goes, "Spare
the rod, spoil the child."
お父さんは 認めません
認めませんよ！
But I won't allow it. I won't allow those
あんな ｺﾞｷﾌﾞﾘ以下の連中と
同じ空気を吸うなんざ｡
lowly cockroaches to breathe
the same air she does!
おい ﾄｼ！
お前 ちょっと土台になれ!!
Hey, Toshi! Be my spotter for a second!!
Hold on!! This is the same as last time!!
(土方)待たんか～い！
前と同じじゃねえか ｺﾚ!!
This time, you're after your
daughter's work friends?!
今度は 娘のﾊﾞｲﾄ仲間か～？
They're not her friends!!
仲間なんかじゃねえ！
あんな ｷﾓﾝﾒﾝｽﾞらは➡
Papa-rin will never allow her to associate
with such disgusting men!!
[Note: Paparin is a cute way of saying "Papa."]
ﾊﾟﾊﾟりん 絶対 認めねえよ！
Shut up!! I took a break
from work to come here.
(土方)やかましいわ！ こっちは
仕事休んでまで 来てやったのに➡
You're just trying to stop your daughter's
work friends from hitting on her?!
ﾊﾞｲﾄ仲間が
娘 口説くのｼﾞｬﾏするだぁ？
やってられねえ 帰る！
おい 待て！
I can't do this. I'm leaving!!
Hey, wait. When did I ask you to do that?
ｵﾚが いつそんなこと頼んだ！
I just want to kill those men.
ｵﾚは ただ あの男どもを
抹殺したいだけ｡
There's no way I'm doing that either!!
(土方)もっと できるか!!
だいたいよ この前みたいに
娘の彼氏との仲を➡
Besides, I can kind of understand it...
If you're trying to get her to break
up with a boyfriend, like before...
裂こうっていうなら
わからなくてもないぜ｡
100歩 譲って｡
I'll give you that...
But this time, they're not even dating.
だけどよ 今回まだ
付き合ってもいねえんだろ!?
口説かれそうってだけだろう｡
They look like they were
just hitting on her.
口説かれてからじゃ遅えんだよ
先手必勝 殺られる前に殺れ！
Once they're hitting on her, it's too late!!
I need to take the initiative. I need to
kill them before they try anything!!
Kondo-san, do something
about this stupid parent.
近藤さんよ この親ﾊﾞｶに
なんとか言ってやってくれよ｡
(近藤)
誰が近藤だ ｢ｺﾞﾘﾗ１３｣ 再び参上｡
Who are you calling Kondo?
Gorilla 13 appears once again!!
Pops, I'll help you out!!
とっつぁん 手伝うぜ!
Sogo 13 appears once again because
this looks interesting.
[Note: Gorilla 13 and Sogo 13 are a parody
of the Golgo 13 manga series.]
(沖田)
｢ｿｳｺﾞ１３｣ おもしろそうなんで➡
再び参上しやした｡
All right, Kondo, you take
the one on the left.
(松平)よ～し 近藤は左のﾔﾂ
総悟は 右｡
Sogo, you take the one on the right.
I'll take out the one in the middle!
(松平)ｵﾚは 真ん中を狙う！
(土方)おい！
Hey!! I told you this is just like last time!!
だから 前と一緒って
言ってんだろうが!!
Anyway, don't do anything rash!!
とにかく 早まったこと
するんじゃねえよ！
要するに ｱｲﾂらを
諦めさせればいいんだろう？
In short, you want them
to give up on her, right?
There are a lot of easier ways to do that.
そんなの 他に方法
いくらでもあるだだろ？
なんなら ｵﾚが
ちょいと行ってくるから｡
I'll go over there and easily settle this.
それで 軽く片付けてきますから｡
ほ～お えれえ
自信がありそうだな｡
Oh? You've got quite a bit of confidence.
そこまで言うなら ﾄｼ
お前に任せてみっか｡
If you go as far as to say that, Toshi,
I guess I'll leave this to you.
(沖田)とっつぁん こんなﾔﾂ
信用しちゃﾀﾞﾒですぜ！
Pops, you can't trust this guy!!
この前の遊園地でも 土壇場で
裏切りやがった野郎でい｡
He's the guy who betrayed
us at the amusement park.
なんなら ｵﾚが行って
あの３人のｹﾂの穴に➡
I'll go.
I'll shove a ton of enemas up their asses
and make them crap their pants.
大量の浣腸でも 突っ込んで
思いっきり脱糞させてやりやすぜ｡
でもよ ﾄｼ
栗子ちゃんは 彼氏が脱糞しても➡
Toshi, Kuriko-chan's the type of girl who isn't disgusted
even if her boyfriend craps his pants.
引かねえ娘さんだぜ？
ｵﾚが脱糞しただけで➡
When I crap my pants, you guys
are so disgusted with me.
ｱﾝﾀら ﾄﾞﾝ引きしたって～のによ
それを どう攻めるつもりだよ｡
How are you going to attack them?
まぁ 待て 近藤 総悟 ﾄｼの野郎が
ここまで言ってるんだ｡
Now, hold on, Kondo, Sogo.
Toshi is pretty confident.
ちょうどいい この前の遊園地の
借りを返してもらおうや｡
This is convenient.
I want you to pay us back for what you
did to us at the amusement park.
なぁ ﾄｼ やってくれるんだろ
やってくれるんだよな？
Come on, Toshi, you'll do it, right?
You will, won't you? I'm counting on you.
おじさん 期待してっから！
♪♪～
Welcome.
(栗子)
いらっしゃいませでございまする｡
♪♪～
Welcome.
ｳﾝｹﾙ 1,520円でござりまする｡
Unkel. That'll be 1,520 yen.
[Note: Unkel is a parody of
Yunker, an energy drink.]
夜のお勤め
お気の毒でござりまする｡
I'm sorry you have to
work so late at night.
ありがとうございましたで
ございまする｡
Thank you very much.
Kuriko-chan. Kuriko-chan, what
do you do on your days off?
栗子ちゃん 栗子ちゃんは
お休みの日なんか➡
何してるのかな～？
I happen to have two tickets for "My Neighbor
Pedro 2: Rodriguez's Day Off."
[Note: "My Neighbor Pedro" is a
parody of "My Neighbor Totoro."]
実は 『となりのﾍﾟﾄﾞﾛ２
ﾛﾄﾞﾘｹﾞｽとの休日』の券が➡
２枚あるんだけど｡
栗子ちゃ～ん！
Kuriko-chan.
実はｵﾚ ｢宇宙船地球号｣って
ﾊﾞﾝﾄﾞ組んでて➡
I happen to be in a band
called Spaceship Earth.
今度 ﾗｲﾌﾞやるんだけどさ｡
We're going to have a concert soon.
Kuriko-chan.
栗子ちゃ～ん
栗子ちゃんは ﾄﾞﾗｲﾌﾞ好き？
Kuriko-chan, do you like going for rides?
I'll take you out to the bay in my 750.
今度 ｵﾚの750で湾岸を…｡
なんだよ 割り込んでくるなよ！
What's your problem?! Don't cut in!!
What about you? No cheating!!
お前こそ 抜け駆けすんな！
You're being a nuisance to Kuriko-chan!!
栗子ちゃんが 迷惑してんだろ！
Who are you calling a nuisance?!
(店員)迷惑とはなんだ 迷惑とは！
(店員)迷惑だから➡
We're calling you a nuisance...
Because you are one!!
迷惑だって言ってるの！
(店員)そうだ そうだ！
That's right!!
《まったく 娘のほうは
相手にしてねえじゃねえかよ｡
His daughter isn't even talking to them.
とっつぁんの
親ﾊﾞｶにも困ったもんだぜ》
Pops sure is troublesome when
he acts like a stupid parent.
(近藤)｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣を 読むﾌﾘしたまま
まったく動きませんね｡
He's just continuing to act as
if he's reading that JUMP.
He's not moving at all.
(松平)なにしてやがるんだ！
(近藤)あっ 動いた！
What is he doing?
He moved!!
He's just turning the page!!
(松平)
ﾍﾟｰｼﾞを めくっただけじゃねえか！
(沖田)本格的に
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣読んでませんか ｱｲﾂ…｡
Is he reading that JUMP for real?
(栗子)あっ
あの本棚のところにいる人…｡
That man by the magazine rack...
I think I've seen him before...
どこかで
見たことがあるような気が…｡
[TEL]
[Katakuriko Matsudaira]
もしもし 土方ですけど｡
Hello? This is Hijikata.
Toshi, how long are you going
to keep reading that JUMP?
[TEL](松平)ﾄ～ｼ～
いつまで ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣読んでんの～？
[TEL]早いとこ 行動してよ！
脱糞でも何でもいいから｡
Get moving already!!
Make them crap their
pants or something.
[TEL]さっさと やってちょうだいませ
さもないと おじさん➡
Just do it! If you don't, I'll cry.
I'll cry while I shoot them.
泣いちゃうからして 泣きながら
撃っちゃおうからして！
(土方)はい わかりやした！
All right.
Oh well, I guess I have to make
them crap their pants.
(土方)しようがねえ！
やっぱ 脱糞か!?
Why don't we watch Pedro?
ﾍﾟﾄﾞﾛどう？ ﾍﾟﾄﾞﾛ｡
Come to my live performance!
ﾗｲﾌﾞ来てよ～！
A ride would be fun!
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾌﾞ楽しいぜ！
ﾍﾟﾄﾞﾛったら ﾍﾟﾄﾞﾛ！
She's going to see Pedro!!
I said that she's going to
my live performance!!
ﾗｲﾌﾞだって言ってんだろう!!
ﾄﾞﾗｲﾌﾞだってば!!
We're going for a ride!!
I'll take this!
これをもらおう！
Oh. Welcome.
あっ いらっしゃいませで
ございまする！
《ﾌｯ… な～に殺しゃしねえ
ちょっと脅すだけよ》
I won't kill them. I'll just scare them.
あっ ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ…｡
Mayonnaise...
あなたは！
It's you!!
You're Mayo 13-sama!
ﾏﾖﾗｻｰﾃｨｰﾝ様！
《しまった！》
Oh no!!
K-K-K-Kuriko-san?
くく… 栗子さん！
(店員)何すか？ その男は!!
W-Who is that man?
どういう関係ですか！
What's your relationship with him?
《ま… 待てよ こりゃ使える》
Wait! I can use this...
あっ…｡
(店員たち)うわぁ～！
ｺｲﾂは ｵﾚの女だ！
She's my woman.
この女と ｵﾚは
どうしようもないﾋﾓ男と➡
Our relationship is like that of a love
affair between a hopeless pimp
深情けの年増女のような
情痴に溺れた関係なんだよ｡
and a loving, middle-aged woman.
すっかり待たせちまったな 栗子｡
Sorry to keep you waiting, Kuriko.
ｵﾚが頼りねえばっかりによぉ…｡
I'm always so unreliable.
だが もう心配いらねえ｡
But you don't need to worry
anymore. I'll always...
ずっと ｵﾒｴを離しはしねえぜ！
be by your side.
ﾏﾖﾗｻｰﾃｨｰﾝ様！
Mayo 13-sama...
わかったか！ ﾃﾒｴら｡
Got that?! Don't ever come
near my woman again!!
二度とｵﾚの女に
近づくんじゃねえぞ～！
近づいたら…➡
If you do...
たたっ斬るから そう思え！
I'll kill you!!
(店員たち)うわぁ～!!
(店員たち)そんなぁ～！
N-No way...
(松平)ふぅ…
これで 一件落着ってか！
Phew... That's one problem solved.
(笑い声)
(賑わい)
(銀時)ったくよ
陽気が よくなるってえと…｡
Jeez!! This happens whenever
the weather's nice.
(神楽)どっから湧いてくるｱﾙか？
Where do they come from?
(新八)盛りのついた
猫みたいですね ﾎﾝﾄ｡
They're like cats in heat. Really...
♪♪～
っつうか どっか行きません？
Anyway, why don't we
go somewhere else?
どっかって どこよ！
お金はないｱﾙよ！
Somewhere else? Where?
We don't have any money.
でも これじゃ…｡
しようがねえ！ じゃあ…｡
But at this rate...
Oh well, in that case...
Wait, wait! Calm down and listen to me.
(土方)待て待て
落ち着いて よ～く聞け！
だから さっきのは
愛の告白なんかじゃなくて➡
That was not a confession of my love.
ｱﾝﾀの親父に
頼まれてやったことなんだ｡
Your father asked me to do that.
つまり 演技なんだよ 演技｡
In other words, I was just acting.
あぁ？ ほら あの
ｺﾝﾋﾞﾆにいただろう 小汚い３人組｡
There were those three shabby guys
at the convenience store, right?
ｱｲﾂらを追い払うために
やったことなんだ！
I did it to scare them away.
その気もないのに あんなこと
言っちまったのは悪かったよ｡
I'm sorry I said that even though
I'm not interested in you.
でも どうやら これでｱｲﾂらも
いなくなったみたいだし➡
But it looks like they're gone
now. I'm going to stop acting.
これで ｵﾚは…｡
《栗子:ﾏﾖﾗ様…｡
Mayo-sama...
ﾏﾖﾗｻｰﾃｨｰﾝ様！》
Mayo 13-sama...
…というわけだ！ わかったかい？
That's the story. Got that?
私 以前
ﾏﾖﾗ様を お見かけして以来➡
I've been in love with you from
the moment I saw you.
ずっと恋焦がれておりました｡
えっ？
もう一度 お会いしたいと
願っておりました！
And I wished that I could see you again.
そうしましたら
その願いが通じたのか➡
And my wish was granted and
we had such a fateful reunion.
先ほどの運命的な再会…｡
それに 強い抱擁… 甘いお言葉…｡
Your embrace was so strong and
your words were so sweet.
私… 天にも昇るような気持で
ございまする！
I felt as if I was ascending to heaven!
ｶｧ～ｯ!! あのね！
Say, are you listening to me?
聞いてる？ あなた 人の話｡
だいたい こんなところを
ｱﾝﾀの親父さんに見つかったら➡
I'd be in an awkward position
if your father saw us here.
ｵﾚ 立場ないからね！ 今度は
ｵﾚが狙撃されちゃうからね!!
He'd shoot me.
だからね 冷たいようだけど➡
I know this is a bit cold, but I don't have
any intention of going out with you.
ｵﾚは ｱﾝﾀと
つき合うつもりはないから！
ｱﾝﾀは ｽﾃｷだよ！
ｽﾃｷでﾁｬｰﾐﾝｸﾞだけども…｡
You're wonderful. You're wonderful
and charming, but...
ﾁｬｰﾐﾝｸﾞだなんて！
Charming, you say?
Hey! Don't just listen to the
parts you want to hear.
《おい！ 自分に
都合のいいところだけ➡
聞こえてんじゃねえよ!!》
いや ﾁｬｰﾐﾝｸﾞっていうのは
あれだよ あれ！
"Charming" is that thing that men say...
男がね 交際を断るときに
礼儀として言っていることで…｡
...when they're politely turning
someone down.
そろそろ
お店のほうに戻らないと…｡
I've got to return to the store.
えっ…｡
次の休日には➡
Huh?!
I think we can have a date
this upcoming weekend.
ゆっくりﾃﾞｰﾄできると思いまする｡
それでは
ごきげんようでございまする！
Until then, take care.
おっ… おい！
H-Hey!!
Why are we suddenly on a
date?! I refused, didn't I?!
なんで すでに
ﾃﾞｰﾄすることになってる？
ｵﾚ断ってるよね つき合わないって
言ってるよね！ ねぇ!!
I told you I wasn't going to go
out with you, right? Right?!
She's not listening.
聞こえてねえ…｡
(ため息)
旦那！
お困りのようじゃありませんか!!
Sir, it looks like something
is bothering you.
話は全部
聞かせてもらいましたよ｡
We heard everything.
ｱﾀｲらは 人の世の縁切りを
金と白米で請け負う別れさせ屋｡
We're professional relationship busters.
We break up people's relationships for
money and white rice. We'll help you.
力になりやすぜ！
(３人)ﾍﾍｯ!!
Y-You saw all of it?!
ﾃﾒｴら 全部 見てたのか？
(３人)うん｡
ﾁｯ！
Tsk. I don't really want your help.
ｵﾚは お前らの力なんか
借りるつもりはねえからな！
ほぅ… ってことは このまま
順調な おつき合いを ご希望で？
Oh? Does this mean you want
to continue your relationship?
さぞかし
ｽﾃｷな新婚生活になるね！
You'll have a wonderful newlywed life.
ﾌﾟｰﾄﾞﾙ連れてﾍﾟｱﾙｯｸ｡
You'll have a poodle and
wear the same clothes.
お手て つないで ｽｰﾊﾟｰにお買い物｡
You'll hold hands as you go shopping
at the supermarket.
(神楽)毎日６時に帰宅｡
You'll come home every day at 6:00.
(神楽)近所づきあいの
ｸﾞﾁを聞きながら食事｡
You'll have dinner as you listen to
her complain about the neighbors.
(神楽)ｽﾃﾃｺ脱いで
風呂に入ろうと思ったら➡
When you're about to take off
your undershirt to take a bath,
最近 下腹がﾒﾀﾎﾞ…｡
you'll realize that your gut
has been getting big.
嫁さんは ﾃﾚﾋﾞに相槌うちながら…｡
Your wife will just talk to
the television and say...
(神楽)おとうさん お給料
もうちょっと何とかならないの？
Honey, can't you make a bit more money?
そんなこと言ってもよぉ
会社も厳しいんだよ～！
That's easy to say... But the company's
having a rough time...
地味で悲惨な未来予想図だ…｡
We predict a bland and terrible future.
Hey, can you really end this charade
without hurting that girl's feelings?
おい ﾎﾝﾄに あの娘を傷つけずに➡
この茶番を
終わらせられるんだろうなぁ？
ﾌｯ… ｵﾚを信じろ！
Believe in me.
♪♪～
Listen up. A man's worth...
いいか！ 男の甲斐性ってのはな➡
is decided when he can get a woman
to dump him instead of dumping her.
女を振るより 振られることだ｡
You need to make sure she no longer has
any interest in you and make her hate you.
いかに 未練を残させないか
嫌いに させるか！
A girl's heart is like cotton candy.
Any little thing can make it shrivel.
(神楽)女の子のﾊｰﾄは
綿菓子ｱﾙ！
(神楽)ちょっとのことで
しぼむものね！
だから 男の ｲﾔなところとか
汚いところを➡
You should just show her the unpleasant
and disgusting side of men.
これでもかと
見せつければいいんだよ｡
略して…➡
In short, it's the "Hijikata-san,
you're disgusting!!" Plan.
｢土方さんって 不潔！｣
作戦ですね！
略して ｢ﾋｼﾞｹﾂ｣ｱﾙ！
"Hijiketsu" for short.
[Note: A compound of "hiji" from "Hijikata"
and "ketsu" from "fuketsu" (disgusting).]
問題は 具体的に
どうやるか？ ですよね？
The problem is what exactly
we should do, isn't it?
ﾄﾞﾒｽﾃｨｯｸﾊﾞｲｵﾚﾝｽに ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙ 酒乱！
Domestic violence, gambling,
drunken frenzies...
There are many things that women don't
like about men, but the one that gets...
男が女に 嫌われる要素は
多々 あるが➡
いちばん 即効性のあるのは
これだい！
the quickest result is this.
実は ﾎﾞｸ…
この手の映画に 目が なくてね…｡
Actually, I only like to watch
movies like this...
♪♪～
[Magical Man-man The Movie Uncensored]
[Note: "Man" is the shortened term of "manko" the slang for "vagina."]
(土方)ﾃﾚﾋﾞじゃ 見られなかった
あの部分が ﾊﾞｯﾁﾘ公開！
I can finally see all those parts
they wouldn't show on TV.
(土方)ﾎﾞｸは
このときを 待っていたんだ！
I've been waiting for this moment.
Wow, this is painful.
これは ｲﾀｲ…｡
(神楽)普通に 引くｱﾙ｡
Most people would be disgusted.
I'm having him act like he's
a hopeless anime otaku.
ﾔﾂには どうしようもねえ
ｱﾆﾒｵﾀｸを 演じてもらう｡
ﾔﾂは 以前
妖刀に とりつかれたときに➡
He's had experience as a hopeless
otaku when he was
ﾄｯｼｰとして
ﾍﾀれたｵﾀｸを 経験済みだしな…｡
possessed by his demonic sword
and turned into Toshi.
女 引かすには
やっぱり ｵﾀｸは 最強ね！
Otaku are the best way
to disgust women.
ｷﾐが ｲﾔだって言うなら
やめてもいいけど…｡
We don't have to watch
it if you don't want to...
I'll watch it when I'm by myself, though...
１人のときに 観にくるけど…｡
ｲﾔで ございまする…｡
やっぱり…？
I don't want to.
I thought so...
私も 一緒に
参りますで ございまする！
But I'll go with you.
Huh?!
あなた様が 好きなものは➡
I want to like the things...
私も
好きになりたいで ございまする｡
that you like.
…ﾏｼﾞでか!?
Really?!
It's a complete failure, Gin-chan.
(神楽)思いっきり 不発ｱﾙよ
銀ちゃん｡
(栗子)あっ！ まもなく➡
(ﾌﾞｻﾞｰ)
Oh, it's going to start soon. Let's hurry.
上映時間で ございまする！
早く早く！
期待どおり
ﾊﾞｯﾁﾘ 丸見えで ございましたね！
As expected, we got to see
all the uncensored parts, huh?!
Why are you happy?
なんで 喜んでんの？
Are you dissatisfied?
ご不満で ございまするか？
もっと 泡が少ないほうが
よかったで ございまするか？
Would it have been better if
there were fewer bubbles?
触手ﾌﾟﾚｲが
足りなかったで ございまするか？
Did it need more tentacles?
(神楽)あのｱﾏ 侮れないｱﾙ！
恐ろしい娘！
That bitch is formidable.
What a terrifying girl.
Why is Kagura-chan getting hostile?
なんで 神楽ちゃんが
対抗心 燃やしてんの？
しようがねえ！
やっぱり あれを出すか！
Oh well. I guess I'll use "that"!
あれ？
あれって 何ね？
"That"?
What is "that"?
(土方)いつもの ２つ｡
(ｵﾔｼﾞ)へいよ！
Two servings of the usual.
Got it.
(栗子)これが ﾏﾖﾗ様の➡
Is this the restaurant you usually go to?
行きつけの お店で
ございまするか…｡
伝統的で 歴史的な空気を
感じるで ございまする｡
It has a very traditional
and historic feel to it.
(ｵﾔｼﾞ)へい お待ち～！
Here you go. Thank you for waiting.
The Hijikata Special, otherwise
known as Dog Food.
｢土方ｽﾍﾟｼｬﾙ｣… 別名 ｢犬の餌｣！
あれを見て ｲﾔな気持にならない
人間が いるだろうか!?
Is there anyone who wouldn't be
disgusted by the sight of that?
ｲﾔな気持っていうか…｡
Disgusted?
I get a sour taste in my mouth
just looking at that.
見てるだけで
口の中 酸っぱいｱﾙ！ うっ…！
これは 何で ござりまするか？
ﾒｼだ｡
What is this?
It's lunch!!
口の中が 味覚のﾜﾝﾋﾟｰｽ!!
The One Piece of flavors is in my mouth!!
It's the Trichiliocosm of flavor!!
味の 三千世界や～!!
お前…
ほんとに うまいと思ってるのか？
Do you really think it's delicious?
はい！ とっても
おいしゅう ございまする！ ｳﾌｯ！
Yes. It's very delicious.
I've found a kindred spirit here of all places.
《こんなところに 同志が…！》
(栗子)なぜ そのようなことを➡
Why do you ask that?
おたずねに なるので
ございまするか？
いや… なんでもねえ！
No... It's nothing.
やばいっすよ～！
This is bad! Hijikata-san was
a little pleased about that!
土方さん
今 ちょっと喜んでましたよ！
ﾏﾖﾗｰ仲間が できたって顔
してましたよ！
He looks happy he's met
a fellow mayo lover.
ﾐｲﾗ取りが ﾐｲﾗね！
He's gone for wool, but
came back shorn.
おいしいものを 教えていただき
ありがとうで ございまする｡
Thank you for introducing me
to something so delicious.
…ほら！
銀さんも 神楽ちゃんも 急いで！
Come on, Gin-san, Kagura-chan, hurry.
な～んか
もう ｱｲﾂら いいんじゃねえ？
They look like they're hitting
it off pretty well.
We should let them get together.
Combine okay?
[Note: Parody of the anime, Chōdenji
Robo Combattler V.]
くっついちゃえば いいんだよ｡
ｺﾝﾊﾞｲﾝ ｵｯｹｰ？
(神楽)なんだかんだ言いつつ
ﾅｲｽｶﾎﾟｰじゃね～？
If anything, they're a nice couple.
You're suddenly giving up?!
いきなり 投げやりになってる！
土方さんが
めっちゃ こっち見てますよ！
Hijikata-san keeps looking at us!
He looks like he thinks everyone
in the world is a liar!
この世の中 すべてが ｳｿつきだ
みたいな目 してますよ！
Oh well. Shall we try the next plan?
しようがねえ…｡
じゃあ 次 一応 やってみる？
ようよう お熱いね～！
Hey, there! Things are getting
pretty passionate here.
ずいぶんと
見せつけてくれんじゃねえの～！
You've been showing off quite a bit!!
女の前だからって
かっこつけてんじゃねえぞ～！
Don't act so cool just because
you've got a woman.
ﾁｬﾗﾁｬﾗ いちゃつきやがって～！
How dare you prance around
and flirt like that.
We'll kill you, damn it!!
ぶっ殺されっぞ この野郎!!
ﾏﾖﾗ様！
Mayo-sama.
す… すいませ～ん!!
I-I'm sorry!!
お気に障ったのなら
いくらでも 謝りますから！
I apologize if I've offended you.
あっ… あの… お金ですね？
U-Umm, money, right? H-Here.
Please take this and spare us.
は… はい！ あの… これ…
これで 勘弁してください！
命だけは… 命だけは
ほんと 勘弁してくださ～い!!
At least spare our lives!!
(土方)靴の裏でも なんでも
なめますんで～!!
I'll do anything. I'll even lick
the soles of your shoes!!
なかなか 素直なｶﾞｷじゃねえか！
What an obedient kid.
ほら！ よこせって!!
Come on, hand it over!!
Lick the sole of my shoes?!
Go ahead and lick them!!
靴の裏 なめるだ～？
なめてもらおうじゃねえかよ～!!
What's this?! There's only
3,000 yen and a Suica.
[Note: A Suica is a smart card used
to pay for train rides in Japan.]
なんだよ ｺｲﾂ！ 3,000円と
SUICAしか 入ってねえぞ～！
ﾃﾒｴ この野郎!!
You bastard!!
大の大人が 3,000円たぁ
どういうことだ～!?
You're an adult and you only have
3,000 yen? You must be kidding!!
You've got more, don't you?!
ほんとは
もっと 持ってんじゃねえか!?
(神楽)ﾌﾝ！
隠してんじゃねえぞ ｺﾗ～!!
Don't hide it!!
Jeez.
いつも ｷｻﾞったらしいｾﾘﾌばっかり
言いやがってよ～!!
How dare you always
use such showy lines!
何回 DVDの表紙になりゃあ
気が済むんだ ｺﾗ～!!
How many DVD covers
have you been on?!
[Note: Hijikata adorns many GinTama DVD covers.]
(神楽)気取ってんじゃねえぞ
ｺﾗ～!!
Don't try to act stylish, damn it!!
How dare your merchandise
sell more than mine?!
[Note: Hijikata’s consumer goods have
more selection than Shinpachi’s.]
何が真選組なんだ お前ら！
Who cares if you're the Shinsengumi's
Vice-Chief?!
おかしいじゃねえか
おかしいだろ!!
ﾃﾒｴら いいかげんにしろよ!!
All of you, cut it out!!
長えよ！ いつまでやってんだよ！
つうか それ ｵﾚのことだろ！
You're taking too long! How
long do you plan on doing this?!
Anyway, you're just talking
about me, aren't you?!
You're talking about my
normal self, aren't you?!
素のｵﾚのことだろ！
何 この機に乗じて➡
Why are you using this moment
日ごろのうっぷん
晴らしてんだよ！
to vent your pent-up anger?!
な… な… この野郎～!!
You bastard!
(栗子)ﾏﾖﾗ様…
さっきは 私のために➡
Mayo-sama, you risked your
life to protect me, didn't you?
命をかけて守ってくれたので
ございまするね？
え？ いや あの その…➡
Huh? Well, umm, uhh… It was a
conditioned reflex or something.
条件反射っつうかなんつうか…｡
照れるなんて
かわいい方でございまする｡
You're getting bashful. That's so cute.
ｷｬｯ！ 私ったら
なんて恥ずかしいことを…｡
How could I say something
so embarrassing?
こんなことを言う 私を➡
Don't hate me…
お嫌いにならないで
くださりませでございませ～｡
for saying that.
もう いや～ もう～！
I don't care what happens anymore.
もうどうなるか 構いやしねえ
ｵﾚは 逃げる！
I'm running away.
逃げるって 土方さん…｡
Running away, Hijikata-san?
そして １人の少女に
一生癒えぬ傷を残すのか？
And leave that girl permanently scarred?
男なら 何人斬ろうがいいんだよ
だがな…➡
It doesn't matter how many men you kill.
You must never betray
a girl's pure feelings.
娘の純情だけは
裏切っちゃいけねえんだ｡
うわっ この人 また
めんどくさいこと言い出したよ｡
Whoa! He's saying obnoxious
things again!
神楽ちゃん 何か 案ないの？
Kagura-chan, do you have
any suggestions?
なもん 別れて逃げれば➡
If he runs away, she'll just forget
him after three days.
女なんて ３日もすれば
忘れるｱﾙ！
こっちは 身も蓋もない
超ﾘｱﾙなこと言ってるよ｡
She's got a harsh and really
plausible opinion.
あ～ ｸｿ… なんで ｵﾚが➡
Aww, crap! Why did this
have to happen to me?
こんなことに 巻き込まれなきゃ
いけねえんだよ？
逃げるのはいいが お前
絶対 あの娘の前に現れない➡
Running away is fine,
but are you prepared to never
appear in front of her again?
覚悟はあるのかよ？
あたりめえだ｡
Of course.
逃げるためには
何でもする覚悟は？
Are you prepared to do
anything to run away?
場合が場合だ｡
できることなら何だってするさ｡
It depends on the situation.
I'll do whatever I can!
本気だろうな？
(土方)ああ｡
You're serious, right?
Yeah.
ﾏﾖﾗ様？ ﾏﾖﾗ様～？
Mayo-sama? Mayo-sama!
どこに
お行きになったのですか～？
Where have you gone?
ﾏﾖﾗ様～!?
(土方)振り向かずに聞いてくれ｡
Mayo-sama!
Listen to me and don't turn around.
ﾏﾖﾗ様…｡
(土方)向くんじゃねえ！
Mayo-sa—
Don't turn around!
(土方)これまで お前には
話してなかったことがある｡
There’s something I haven't told you.
何でございまするか？
(土方)実は ｵﾚは…➡
What is it?
I'm actually…
ﾏﾖﾗｰ星の王子なんだﾏﾖ｡
The Prince of the Planet
Mayo Maniac, mayo.
王子…!?
A prince?!
(土方)向いてもいいﾏﾖ｡
You can turn around now, mayo.
《やっぱり ﾀﾞﾒか…｡
It's useless. There's no way
this is going to work.
いくらなんでも
こんなの通用するわけ…》
I thought so.
(栗子)やっぱり
そうだったでございまするね｡
何か 普通の人にはないｵｰﾗを
私 感じていたでございまする！
I sensed that you were
not a normal person.
《通用した！
語尾が ﾏﾖなのに通用した！》
It worked!! I've added “mayo” to the
end of my sentences and it worked!!
ｵﾚは 地球に長くいると
死んでしまうﾏﾖ｡
I'll die if I stay on Earth too long, mayo.
どうやら 限界がきてしまったﾏﾖ｡
It seems I'm at my limit, mayo.
行ってしまうので
ございまするか？
Are you going?
(土方)そろそろ
お迎えが来る頃ﾏﾖ｡
I'm going to be picked up shortly, mayo.
私も連れていって！
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞなら 私…➡
Take me with you.
I don't mind eating mayonnaise
for every meal.
３食でも平気でございまする！
私… 私…！
I-I…
お願い！ 一緒に
行きたいでございまする！
Please.
I want to go with you.
《なんか 余計
まずい方向にいってない？ これ！
This is headed in the wrong
direction, isn't it?
いや… ふんばれ 十四郎！
お前ならやれるはず…》
No, hold on, Toshiro!! You can do this.
ば… ﾊﾞｶなこと言うんじゃないﾏﾖ｡
D-Don't be silly.
ﾏﾖﾗｰ星は 大気がすべて
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞでできた辺境の星ﾏﾖ｡
Planet Mayo Maniac is a remote planet covered
in a mayonnaise atmosphere, mayo.
とても ｷﾐが生きていける
星じゃないﾏﾖ｡
You wouldn't be able to
survive there, mayo.
なっ ｷﾐは 地球で生きていくのが
いちばんいいﾏﾖ｡
It's best if you live on Earth, mayo.
ｵﾚは いつでも
ｷﾐのことを見守ってるﾏﾖ｡
I'll always be watching over you, mayo.
Always?
いつでも でございまするか？
お… おぅﾏﾖ｡
Y-Yeah, mayo!
どうしたﾏﾖ？
What's wrong, mayo?
私 お別れだからって…➡
Even though this is goodbye.
涙は 絶対に
流さないでございまする｡
I won't cry.
♪♪～
Prince, it's time, mayo.
王子様 そろそろ時間ﾏﾖ｡
(神楽)お迎えでごんすﾏﾖ｡
We've come for you, mayo.
ｷﾐも幸せに暮らすﾏﾖ！
Live happily, mayo!
(栗子)ﾏﾖﾗ様！
出発進行ﾏﾖ｡
Mayo-sama…
We're leaving, mayo.
Mayo!
(神楽/新八)ﾏﾖ！
ﾏﾖﾗ様！
Mayo-sama…
ﾏﾖﾗ様～！
さよならでございまする～！
Mayo-sama!
Farewell!
(土方)
さよならﾏﾖ！ さよならﾏﾖ～！
Farewell, mayo…
ﾏﾖﾗ様 きっと… きっとまた
会えるでございまする｡
Mayo-sama… I'm sure
that we'll meet again.
Kuriko-san is a pretty nice girl.
結構 いい娘だったっすね
栗子さん｡
Yeah…
そうだなぁ…
え？ どうした？ 王子…｡
What's wrong, prince?
さては お前… あの娘に…｡
Did you fall in love with…
You idiot, it's not like that!!
(土方)
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！ そんなんじゃねえっ!!
(銀時/新八/神楽)ﾍﾍﾍﾍ～！
♪♪～
(土方)…てぇことだﾏﾖ｡
That's my story, mayo.
すげえ ﾑｶつくﾏﾖ｡
You're really annoying, mayo.
[GinTama The Animation]
Long, long ago… Urashima
[Note: Urashima Taro is the story of a fisherman who rescues a turtle and is rewarded with a visit to Ryugu Palace under the sea.]
caught a voyeuristic turtle…
When he went to Ryugu Palace…
[A Summer Vacation Special Project]
[Ryugu Arc]
Really?! Huh?! It exists?
Ryugu Palace really exists?!
[Taken by a turtle they save…]
It ordinarily exists…
[A big showdown in the south seas…]
This is terrible.
Our boats heading to Ryugu
Palace were destroyed
[A story of seven men and women?]
[Note: Title of a Japanese TV series from the 80s.]
and we ended up on this deserted island.
I am the most beautiful
creature in the world.
[Otohime's plot draws near!!]
I am Otohime, the ruler of Ryugu.
My worst summer vacation
was about to begin.
["Summer Vacation is the Most
Fun Right Before It Begins"]
[Tsk! That's great… Summer vacation
starts from next week on…]
[I have to work every week.
I don't get any breaks. (Sob)]